Joy Baker

Bobby Baker

Microservices Engineer

Global,

+1-513-404-4499

bob@arvo.technology

http://bobbybakes.github.io/

English

BACKGROUND

ABOUT

A Senior Software Engineer with over 10 years of experience with 5 years experience in the development and architecture of microservices. A versatile engineer with expertise in cross-platform products, security protocols, and efficient data solutions. Accomplished in leading teams to deliver solid systems and applying best practices in software development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Blockchain Hackathon -2nd Place Winner,

Jun, 2021 - Jul, 2021 16 days

IBC Challenge: Build a blockchain application that utilizes IBC, or build a novel use case for the IBC protocol.

- Built in Go, this project is designed to demonstrate the use of IBC between different zones in the Cosmos ecosystem for privacy preserving credential management.
- $\verb| o https://github.com/whalelephant/CertX| \\$

Mobile Engineer, X-Team

Dec, 2020 - Apr, 2022 1 year 4 months

Swift / Kotlin

- Converting Android / iOS to KMM Shared Libraries.
- Fixing legacy iOS issues.
- SwiftUI development.
- Fixing legacy Android issues.

Microservices Engineer, ETCH

Sep, 2018 - Present

Microservices Architecture / Development

• Architected and developed event based cloud solutions to provide secure APIs and real time data solutions in the transportation industry.

Microservices Engineer, X-Team

Sep, 2018 - Oct, 2020 2 years 1 month

Go / Node Microservices Development

- Developed Microservices in Node.js and GoLang to serve low-latency streaming to platforms such as web and native devices.
- Responsible for migrating Node.js Microservices to GoLang.

Software Journeyman / Microservices Engineer, Pillar Technology

Oct, 2016 - Sep, 2018 1 year 10 months

Extreme Programming

- · Architected and developed a Big Data platform to advance data science within the automotive industry. Built with AWS and Hadoop.
- · Developed internal iOS applications for clerical tasks.
- Developed Android and Embedded devices in the automotive industry.
- · Developed a cyber security solution, using advanced analytics to aggregate and identify malicious threats and vulnerabilities.
- · Developed applications and provided agile consulting on an embedded software project in the automotive industry.

Senior Developer, IT Applications, Nationwide Insurance

Aug, 2014 - Oct, 2016

2 years 2 months

J2EE, customer-facing web applications

- Tech Lead / Mentor
- o Java / Spring MVC

GIS Analyst and Software Developer, Stantec

Apr, 2012 - Aug, 2014

2 years 4 months

GIS Development and Analytical Cartography

- o Interactive Mapping Applications and Add-ons
- FEMA floodplain mapping
- Cartography

GIS Specialist, The Ohio Department of Natural Resources

Jan, 2008 - Apr, 2012

4 years 3 months

GIS Analyst

Groundwater Resource Mapping

SKILLS

Native Development

Flutter ReactNative Android iC

API Development

Golang Python NodeJS

MEAN

Mongo Express Angular 1/2 Node

J2EE

WebSphere Java JSP Gradle Maven Groovy Spring MVC

Microservices

Vert.x AWS LINKERD Nginx Serverless.io

Big Data

Hadoop HBASE SPARK

Dev Ops

Jenkins AWS Docker Appcenter

EDUCATION

Free Diving		
Wave3 35 meters PB		
Kayaking		
Fishing Extreme Leisure		
Hiking		
Backpacking		
Photography		
Sony Alpha		